**Data and Privacy**

Data and Privacy
================

We are very pleased about your interest in axelspringer.com. With this Privacy Policy, we aim to inform you about how, why and to what extent we process personal data, and what your rights are as a Data Subject.

**Data Controller**
-------------------

Unless otherwise stated in this Privacy Policy, the Data Controller in accordance with Art. 4 no. 7 GDPR is Axel Springer SE, Axel-Springer-Str. 65, 10888 Berlin, Germany, Phone: +49 30 2591 0, E-Mail: [kontakt@axelspringer.de](mailto:kontakt@axelspringer.de) (hereinafter also “we” or “us”).

**Accessing the website**
-------------------------

When you use our site, in order to enable the usability of the functions provided and to ensure the security and stability of our site, we set absolutely necessary cookies and collect and process the following information. Cookies are small text files that are transferred from the Internet to your computer along with the data actually requested. This data is stored there and kept ready for later retrieval. In particular, we use cookies to collect the following information:

* Information about the end device accessing the site and the software used
* Date and time of the access
* Websites from which the user has accessed our website or which the user accesses through our website
* IP address

The processing of your IP address is necessary in order to deliver our services to your device. The legal basis for the data processing is Art. 6 par. 1 lit. b DSGVO. In addition, our servers store your IP address for up to 14 days for our own security purposes (Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f DSGVO).

**Newsletter**
--------------

If you have subscribed to one of our notification services or newsletters, we will use your e-mail address to send you the newsletter that you have subscribed to. The legal basis for data processing is provided by Art. 6 para. 1 point a GDPR. You can withdraw your consent at any time with future effect or unsubscribe from the subscribed newsletter, for example by clicking on the unsubscribe link provided for this purpose in each newsletter.

These e-mails feature “tracking pixels” for the purpose of and in service of our interest in optimising our newsletter. This provides us with information about which browser and which operating system is being used, which IP address is currently accessing it, and also who the provider is. It is also used to detect if the e-mail has been read and whether the link integrated into the e-mail has been clicked on, such that the website has been visited from that IP address. Moreover, it is used to count the number of accesses to the website and the relevant time of day when the e-mail was opened and the access was performed. The approximate location of the user is also identified by these means. If you do not wish to be tracked in this fashion, you can unsubscribe from the newsletter at any time as described above. The legal basis for data processing is provided by Art. 6 para. 1 point f GDPR.

Business partner check
----------------------

If you act as our business partner, we are obliged to process your personal data (name, address, internet address if applicable) on the basis of the relevant sanctions list regulations of the EU, the UK and the USA, insofar as this is necessary for compliance with these legal requirements. This includes in particular the processing of personal data by Axel Springer SE in the course of the comparison with applicable sanctions lists and the regular repetition of such comparisons when sanctions lists are updated or you as a business partner update your data. The legal basis for data processing is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. c GDPR in conjunction with Art. 6 para. 3 GDPR.

**Contact initiated by you**
----------------------------

When you contact us, for example using one of our contact forms or e-mail addresses, the data that you provide (your e-mail address, possibly your name and your telephone number) will be processed by us for the purpose of responding to your enquiry. We will delete data collected in this connection once it is no longer required for the aforementioned purpose, unless the deletion of this data would contravene statutory retention obligations. The legal basis for data processing is provided by Art. 6 para. 1 sentence 1 point f GDPR.

**Place of Processing**
-----------------------

We also process data in countries outside of the European Economic Area (“EEA”), for example in the USA. To ensure that a suitable level of data protection is observed, we make use of the EU Standard Contractual Clauses for the preparation of the contracts with services employed in Third Countries as per Art. 46 para. 2 point c GDPR, unless there is an adequacy decision issued by the European Commission for that Third Country:

**Transmission of Data**
------------------------

Unless otherwise stated in this Privacy Policy, we will only transmit your personal data to third parties if transmission is required to comply with our contractual obligations to you and this evidently needs to be done through or jointly with another provider, if we are permitted or required by law to transmit the data on other grounds, or if you have provided us with the relevant consent.

**Cookies and similar Technologies**
------------------------------------

In order to provide our service, ensure security and prevent fraud, the use of cookies and similar technologies is necessary (core services).Your Privacy Settings and your cookie settings (regarding permitted/blocked cookies) are also stored on your end device. The use of cookies is required for us to provide you with the service requested by you. Please refer to the Privacy Settings for further information on these special categories of cookies.

Cookies are small files that your browser places in a folder designated for this purpose on your device. This makes it possible, for instance, to determine whether you have visited a website before. Many cookies contain what is known as a “cookie ID”. A cookie ID is a unique cookie identifier. It consists of a string of characters which websites and servers can associate with the specific web browser where the cookie has been stored. This enables visited websites and servers to differentiate between the specific browser of the Data Subject and other web browsers containing different cookies. A specific web browser can be recognised and identified using the unique cookie ID. Without additional information, cookies cannot be used to identify you personally.

Unless otherwise agreed, we and our partners will only employ other cookies and similar technologies with your consent expressed through corresponding Privacy Settings. These cookies are used by ourselves and our partners to store and process data on your end device for the purposes listed below in this Privacy Policy. If consent is not granted for the setting of cookies, it may not be possible to fully use all functions of our website.

More information on the cookies used and equivalent technologies and our partners is provided in the relevant parts of this Privacy Policy and your Privacy Settings, where you can withdrawal your consent with future effect at any time. Previously created cookies can also be deleted by you at any time using your web browser or another software solution. This is possible in all standard web browsers. Please note that this will also delete any settings you have made in your Privacy Settings, such that these will need to be reconfigured when you visit our website again. The duration of the cookies is limited to a maximum of one year unless otherwise stated.

Privacy
-------

The vast majority of the services or content of the third-party providers are only loaded and the relevant data processing only takes place if you have previously declared your consent within the meaning of Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a DSGVO or, with regard to cookies and similar technologies, according to § 25 para. 1 TDDDG. In addition, there are a few cookies or similar technologies that are absolutely necessary to provide the service you requested (Section 25 (2) TDDDG) (special category absolutely necessary), as well as certain downstream data processing based on certain legitimate interests pursuant to. Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f GDPR; the setting of cookies or data processing in these constellations is carried out without consent, although we give you the opportunity to object to the data processing based on Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f GDPR.

In order to map this process for you in a user-friendly way with all legal requirements but also all necessary information, a window (“Privacy”) opens when you first visit our website, in which you have the option, through appropriate settings, to give your consent to third-party providers to store and/or retrieve information in your device as well as to process personal data for specific purposes, to refuse this in each case or – insofar as the processing of personal data is based on the legal basis of legitimate interests (Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f GDPR) – to object.

In the following, we inform you about the use of cookies or comparable technologies and the processing of personal data by the third-party providers we use, which may take place in each case depending on the privacy settings you have made.

**Content Performance Measurement**
-----------------------------------

With your consent, we use services for the purpose of measuring the performance of content on our service. These services collect metrics and provide reports on the deployment of content to users and how these users interact with this content. The legal basis for data processing is provided by Art. 6 para. 1 point a GDPR. You have the ability to withdraw any consent you have issued at any time under the Privacy Settings. We also make use of the services of the third-party providers listed below, who serve pursuant to Art. 4 no. 7 GDPR as the Data Controllers for the data processing performed via their respective services. Please refer to the Privacy Policies of the third-party providers linked below for more information on how they process data and on your rights as a Data Subject:

* Adobe Analytics (Adobe Systems Software Ireland Limited, 4-6 Riverwalk, Citywest Business Campus, Dublin 24, Republic of Ireland), [https://www.adobe.com/privacy.html](https://www.adobe.com/privacy.html), integrated via Tealium Tag Management (Tealium Inc., 11095 Torreyana Road, San Diego, CA 92121, USA) [https://tealium.com/privacy/](https://tealium.com/privacy/). The tag management itself does not store any personal data from you. Only anonymized data is generated.

**Integration of third-party Providers**
----------------------------------------

For the purpose of enhancing the user experience in our service, we also embed services of the third-party providers listed below, each of which serves as the respective Data Controller in accordance with Art. 4 no. 7 GDPR. With your consent declared in the Privacy Settings, your browser will establish a direct connection with the server of the relevant third-party provider. In this case, the third-party provider will always process your IP address, which is necessary to establish a connection to the server of the third-party provider and to deliver the content. The legal basis for the integration of these services is provided by Art. 6 para. 1 point a GDPR. You may withdraw consent that you have previously issued at any time with future effect in your Privacy Settings. Information on how each third-party provider processes data can be found in the respective third-party provider’s Privacy Policy.

* Google Maps (Google Ireland Limited, Gordon House, Barrow Street, Dublin 4, Ireland), [https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=de&gl=de](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=de&gl=de)
* Instagram (Meta Platforms Ireland Limited, 4 Grand Canal Square, Dublin 2, Ireland), [https://www.instagram.com/legal/privacy/](https://www.instagram.com/legal/privacy/)
* LinkedIn (LinkedIn Ireland Unlimited Company, Wilton Place, Dublin 2, Ireland), [https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy?](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy?)
* Soundcloud (SoundCloud Limited, Rheinsberger Str. 76/77, 10115 Berlin, Germany), [https://soundcloud.com/pages/privacy](https://soundcloud.com/pages/privacy)
* Spotify (Spotify AB, Regeringsgatan 19, SE-111 53 Stockholm, Sweden), [https://www.spotify.com/de/legal/privacy-policy](https://www.spotify.com/de/legal/privacy-policy)
* Twitter (Twitter, Inc., 1355 Market Street, Suite 900, San Francisco, CA 94103, USA), [https://twitter.com/de/privacy](https://twitter.com/de/privacy)
* Vimeo (Vimeo, Inc., 555 West 18th Street, New York, New York 10011, USA), [https://vimeo.com/privacy](https://vimeo.com/privacy)
* Xing (New Work SE, Dammtorstraße 30 20354 Hamburg, Germany), [https://privacy.xing.com/de/datenschutzerklaerung](https://privacy.xing.com/de/datenschutzerklaerung)
* YouTube (Google Ireland Limited, Gordon House, Barrow Street, Dublin 4, Ireland), [https://support.google.com/youtube/answer/7671399?p=privacy\_guidelines&hl=de&visit\_id=0-636644030056539000-341535836&rd=1](https://support.google.com/youtube/answer/7671399?p=privacy_guidelines&hl=de&visit_id=0-636644030056539000-341535836&rd=1)

**Storage Duration**
--------------------

We will only process personal data as long as it is necessary for the relevant purpose stated above. Personal data will then be deleted unless data erasure is prohibited by a statutory retention period.

**Contact Details and your Rights as a Data Subject**
-----------------------------------------------------

Should you have any queries or comments on data protection and privacy or wish to exercise your rights as a Data Subject, please contact our Data Protection Officer at any time:

Axel Springer SE  
Data Privacy  
Axel-Springer-Str. 65  
10888 Berlin  
Germany  

**Information and Rectification**
---------------------------------

You can receive information at any time and at no charge about whether we are processing personal data related to you and also about which information we are specifically storing about you. You are also entitled to receive a copy of the stored information. You can also have errors in your data corrected and missing information completed.

**Erasure, Restriction of processing and “Right to be forgotten”**
------------------------------------------------------------------

You can request that your data be erased and its processing restricted. Where erasure of your personal data is prohibited by statutory retention obligations, your data will be marked with the aim of restricting its future processing.

**Data Portability**
--------------------

Where applicable, you also have the right to have your personal data transmitted to you or to another Data Controller in a structured, standardised and machine-readable format, as long as processing is performed on the basis of consent or contract using automated procedures. This does not apply, however, where the processing is necessary for the performance of a task carried out in the public interest or in the exercise of official authority vested in the controller. You also have the right to have the personal data transmitted directly from one Data Controller to another, provided that it is technically feasible to do so and does not infringe upon the rights and freedoms of other persons.

**Withdrawal of Consent, Objecting to processing**
--------------------------------------------------

**You can withdraw your previously-given consent at any time with future effect by contacting the aforementioned address.**

**Moreover, you have the right to object to the processing of your personal data at any time (where such processing is based on a legitimate interest) for reasons arising from your particular circumstances. This also applies to profiling activities based on these provisions. If such an objection is received, we will cease to process the personal data unless we can demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds for the processing that override the interests, rights and freedoms of the Data Subject, of if the processing is for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims.**

**If we are processing personal data for the purpose of direct marketing, you have the right to object to the processing of your personal data at any time for the purpose of such marketing by contacting the aforementioned address. This also applies to profiling insofar as it is connected with such direct marketing. You also have the right to file an objection for reasons arising from your particular circumstances against processing of your personal data that we are engaged in for scientific, historical research or statistical purposes, unless such processing is required to perform a task that is in the public interest.**

**Right of Complaint**
----------------------

You also have the right to submit a complaint to the competent supervisory authority and to seek legal remedies. The supervisory authority with whom the complaint was lodged will notify the complainant about the status and result of their complaint, including the option of seeking a judicial remedy.

**Last revised:** May 23, 2024

[](https://www.linkedin.com/company/axelspringer/ "LinkedIn")[](https://twitter.com/axelspringer "X (Twitter)")[](https://www.youtube.com/axelspringer "Youtube")[](https://www.instagram.com/axelspringer_se/ "Instagram")

© Axel Springer SE 2024  
Axel Springer is the media and tech company.
